熱い…
It's hot...
Burning...
焼ける
My body...
体が
My throat...
喉が
Burning!
焼ける
It's all right now.
もう大丈夫だから
Just relax and sleep.
安心して寝てていいの
Who are you?
お前は…
あは
まだ動いちゃだめですよ
You mustn't move around just yet.
You're still in pain, aren't you?
まだ痛むんですね
Who are you?
君は…
ああ　私
My name's Eruruu.
エルルゥって言います
Eruruu?
エルルゥ？
And this is my house.
それで ここは私の家です
自分は いったい…
What happened to me?
ああ その
Well, I found you collapsed in the forest.
あなたは森で倒れていたんです
You had terrible injuries when I found you.
見つけた時は ひどい怪我をしていて
Injuries?
怪我？
はい
Ah, well, you'll be all right now.
今はもう大丈夫です
You're through the worst of it,
that's what Grandma says.
峠を越したって
おばあちゃんが言ってましたから
Are you the one who saved me?
君が助けてくれたのか
I...
私は…
自分は
Yes?
はい？
I do not know myself.
分からない
自分は
You don't know...
分からないって…
Tell me!
教えてくれ
Uh, well...
あ あの
Who in the world am I?
自分は
いったい
誰だ
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空 果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に 充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼（はね）を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ 行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから 一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は 色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
Something Uninvited
Why won't it come off?
なぜ外れない
What is it for?
何のために…
Looks like you've come to.
気がついたようだね
What? Don't you have anything to say
to the one who saved your life?
恩人にご挨拶無しかい？
Grandma, he's...
おばあちゃん この人は
Yes, I know. Don't you worry, Eruruu.
分かっておる
エルルゥは心配しなくてもええ
Who in the world am I?
自分は いったい…
I'd like to know the answer myself.
こっちが聞きたいくらいじゃ
And this mask...
この仮面は…
Well, if it doesn't come off, that's how it is.
ま 外れないなら 外れないなりに
All I'll say is that there's probably some reason.
理由があるんだろうて
For now, you should just take it easy and focus
on getting yourself back into shape.
今はゆっくり体を治すことに
専念するがいいさね
Well...
あの
I made some rice porridge for you,
mororo porridge.
おかゆを作ってきたんです
モロロがゆ
Mororo?
モロロ？
You need to get a little nutrition in you.
少し栄養のあるものをとらないと
Oh, right.
Thank you.
ありがとう
It's nothing. I'm a healer's apprentice,
so it's only natural...
い いえ
私 薬師の見習いとして
当然のことを… はあっ
Here now, it's going to get cold.
ほら 冷めちゃいますよ
Actually, I guess it still is kinda hot.
って まだ熱いですね
うーん　息子の古着じゃったが
Those are my son's old clothes,
but it looks like they fit you just right.
ちょうどええようじゃのう
Eruruu...
エルルゥ
That's great! A perfect fit!
よかった　ぴったりですね
So, do you mean to go out and about then?
じゃが もう動き回るつもりかの？
Yes, I can't allow myself to be
in your care forever.
ええ　いつまでも
世話になるわけにはいきませんから
But it might be better if you
get some more rest.
でも まだ安静にしていた方が
You go along with him, Eruruu.
エルルゥ ついていっておやり
Huh!?
We can't have him collapsing again
while he's out. Now, can we?
また行き倒れになられても困るからね
Grandma...
おばあちゃん
Keep a good eye on him.
ちゃんと面倒見るんだよ
Grandma!
おばあちゃん
All right?
いいね？
Right!
はーい
Oh, come on, Aruruu.
You'll have to introduce yourself!
もう アルルゥ　ちゃんとご挨拶しないと
Well, this is my little sister, Aruruu.
えーと 妹のアルルゥです
- Hey...
- Wrong!
やあ
違う
It seems there has been some
sort of misunderstanding.
何か誤解されてしまったようだ
I think she was surprised when she saw
you wearing our father's clothes.
あの子
あなたが お父さんの服を
着ているのを見て
驚いたんだと思います
Now that you mention it,
I have not seen him yet.
そういえば 姿を見ないが
Our father passed away.
お父さんは亡くなりました
Our mother did too, shortly after
giving birth to Aruruu.
お母さんも アルルゥを産んで すぐに…
Then you cannot lend me something
so important to you!
そんな大事な物を借りるわけには
No, it's all right. Don't worry.
気にしないでください
It happened back when we
were both very little.
私達が小さい頃のことですから
I appreciate you lending me your shoulder,
but this is only going to tire you out.
肩を貸してくれるのは ありがたいが
これでは君の方が疲れてしまう
I'll be all right.
Country women are strong after all.
大丈夫です
辺境の女は強いんですから
What's that?
何だ？
Say, is something...
あの 何か？
ひゃあ！
ほやほやほあ…
はっ　嫌！
No!
Are you all right!?
あっ ちょ 大丈夫ですか？
Well, I can see that country women
certainly are strong.
確かに 辺境の女は強いな
わあ　ふっ
That's what happens when you grab a
girl's tail like that all of a sudden!
急に女の子の尻尾を
触ったりするからです
So that thing is real?
それ本物だったのか
What do you mean?
何言ってるんですか？
Teoro-san...
テオロさん
よっと
So you're the one?
あんたかい？
The weird guy who was carried to
the village chief's house?
村長んとこに
担ぎ込まれたっていう 変な奴ぁ
Weird?
変？
でへっ
だーっはっはっはっ！ 本当だ
It's true! You got a weird
mask there, dontcha'?
変な面だなあ　え？
Man, I sure am sorry about that!
いやあー すまねえ すまねえ
We don't get many visitors out here
other than soldiers fleeing battle.
落人以外の客なんて珍しいからよ
You get people fleeing battle here?
落人がいるんですか？
Every now and then, yeah.
たまーにな
It's 'cuz this place is more
peaceful than other parts.
ここは よそよりは平和だからなあ
So we'll see 'em come running
once in a while.
時々流れてくんだよ
It's just a tiny village with
nothing going on really,
何もねえ小さな村だけどよ
皆それなりに楽しく暮らしてんだ
but we still enjoy our lives in our own way.
It seems like there are quite a few
houses undergoing repairs.
何か 修理中の家が多いですね
Yeah, there was this huge
earthquake the other day.
ああ　この間 でけえ地震があってなあ
Earthquake?
地震？
Aruruu didn't come home right after that,
and Eruruu raised havoc.
そんな時に アルルゥが
けぇってこねえもんだから
エルルゥが大騒ぎよ
Oh, good grief! Everything turned out
okay, so what's the big deal?
もう 無事だったんだから
いいじゃないですか
うん　だっはっはっ…！ ちげぇねえ
That's for sure!
An earthquake...
地震…
What's wrong?
どうしたんですか？
Oh, nothing...
いや
Hey, you!
こーらぁー！
でえ！
Honey!
母ちゃん！
Slacking off again when you
should be on the job!
あんた また仕事ほっぽり出して！
Hey, I already worked until sunrise, didn't I?
お天道さんが昇るまで働いたんだから
Isn't that enough?
もういいじゃねえかあ
Don't you give me that self-centered talk.
勝手なこと言わないの！
Yer gonna rip it off! I'm sorry!
えっと ソポク姉さん
Sopoku-neesan!
ん？ あら
Huh? Oh!
My, my...
You must be the strange man that's been
staying at Eruruu's house.
エルルゥの家に
転がり込んできた変な男って
Good grief, not you too, Sopoku-neesan!
もう
ソポク姉さんまで
ふーん
This is pretty aggressive for a
late bloomer like you, Eruruu.
奥手のエルルゥにしちゃ
積極的じゃないさ
Huh?
Well, you see he's injured, so I... I...
この人怪我で　それで その…
あっははは！ はあ　安心したよ
That's a relief.
I see how it is.
そうかい エルルゥがねえ
Well, I don't really know if
you're a nice guy or not,
あんた いい男…
かどうかは分かんないけど
but please take good care of
Eruruu for us, all right?
エルルゥをよろしく頼むよ
はあっ　ソポク姉さん！
Sopoku-neesan!
Hey!
Oh, hey there!
よう！
Hiya!
ははっ　早く 早く
Hurry, hurry!
Wait up!
待って！
えっへ！
ひゃあ！
Hey, you! Stop right...
こら！ 待ちなさ…
Are you all right? Do you feel any pain?
大丈夫ですか？
痛みませんか？
I'm just a little tired, that's all.
ちょっと疲れただけだから
It's because I made you to overdo it.
私が無理をさせてしまったから
I'm the one who said I wanted to go out.
自分から外へ出たいと言ったんだ
It is not your fault at all.
君のせいじゃないよ
But...
でも
It's okay. Thank you.
大丈夫だよ　ありがとう
お おほん！ はあ
We'll go back to the house after
you've had a rest.
ひと休みしたら 家に戻りますから
All right.
ああ 分かった
ガウウー！ ウウ
What's the matter?
どうしたんだ？
You rest here. I'll be right back.
休んでいてください　すぐ戻りますから
-どうしよう…
-クッソ
よーく聞け！
Listen up!
You are now going to offer up
your yearly tribute to us.
今から また年貢を上げることになった
What we take will be a sacrifice for your country.
I'm sure you're delighted.
お国のために身を
捧げられるわけだ　嬉しいだろ
No! You're being unreasonable!
そんな　むちゃくちゃだ！
Silence! You just do exactly as we say.
黙れ
お前らは俺達の言うことに
従ってればいいんだよ
Nuwangi!
ヌワンギ
Huh?
Hey, Eruruu! I rushed here today
so that I could see ya!
よおー エルルゥ！
今日もお前に会うために
すっ飛ばしてきたんだぜえ
なあ　どうだ いいウォプタルだろ
Whaddya think? Nice woptar, isn't he?
He's a little on the wild side, which is why
I'm the only one who can ride...
ちょいと気性が荒いから
俺にしか乗りこなせない…
いったあー！ クソッ
…の野郎 ご主人様に逆らいやがって！
Sonnuva bitch, how dare you
bite your master!?
ちっ　いたたたぁ… はあ
Who was that? Who's laughing!?
誰だー！ 笑ってる奴は！
Jeez, snickering to yourselves...
ちっ コソコソと
Typical for a bunch of hicks!
これだから田舎もんは
Don't talk like that.
そんな言い方はやめて
You shouldn't speak so poorly of
the place where you were born.
自分の生まれた所を悪く言うなんて
Jeez, I do not want to hear it!
あー 聞きたくない 聞きたくない
You never used to talk like that.
昔は そんなこと言う人じゃなかったのに
That was then and this is now.
昔は昔 今は今だ
Nuwangi...
ヌワンギ…
Lord Nuwangi...
ヌワンギ様
Lord Nuwangi!
ああ 聞こえてるよ！
I heard you, damn it!
徴収 終わりました
We have finished collecting the goods.
Fine, then go on ahead.
ああ 先に行ってろ
Sir!
-ああ…
-クソ
Why would you do such a cruel thing?
どうして　こんな ひどいことを
You see, Eruruu, I'm too big a guy to be
living out in the boondocks like this.
俺はなあ エルルゥ　こんな辺境で
満足している器じゃないんだよ
C'mon, you're coming with me.
さあ 来るんだ
I thought I promised you.
I said I'd take you with me.
約束したはずだぜ
お前を連れていくってなあ
I don't remember any promise like that!
そんな約束
Why not!?
何でだ　俺がぜいたくを
させてやるって言ってんだよ
I'm telling you that I'll treat
ya to a life of luxury!
I don't have any need to live in luxury.
私 ぜいたくな暮らしなんかいらない
Don't you lie to me!
嘘つくな！
There ain't a single person in this world
who doesn't want that!
ぜいたくな暮らしがしたくない奴なんて
この世にゃいねえ！
That's not what I want!
うっ そんなの望んでない
Why? Why not!?
何でだ　何でだよ！
Ow! Let go!
嫌 離して！
Can't you see she is not willing to go?
嫌がってるのが分からないのか？
Who the hell are you!?
誰だ お前！
If I only knew, then I would not
have to suffer either.
それが分かれば 自分も苦しまない
I haven't seen you around.
見かけない奴だなあ
You take that mask off now and
tell me who you are, buddy!
お前 その面を取って
このヌワンギ様に挨拶しな！
I cannot remove this mask, and I have
no reason to introduce myself to you.
この仮面は外せないし
お前に挨拶する理由も無い
What!?
俺様が誰だか分かってねえようだな
I seems you don't know who I am, do ya?
Couldn't care less.
知らん
だあ　ううっ
This is exactly why hicks are
such a pain to deal with.
これだから田舎もんは困るぜ
俺様はヌワンギ！
I am Nuwangi!
I happen to be the son of the king's....
何を隠そう この国の皇（オゥルォ）
younger brother, who is the lord of this area,
Lord Sasante.
…の弟で
ここを統治する藩主ササンテの息子だ
はん？
So overcome with fear ya can't even talk, huh?
恐怖のあまり声も出ねえかあ
Hey, Eruruu, how long have you been letting
this weirdo hang around the village?
なあ エルルゥ
いつから こんな怪しい奴を
村に住まわせてんだ？
You gotta run his ass out!
とっとと追い出しちまえよ
I guess I could just do that
right here and now...
何だったら 俺が この場でよお
やめて！
Stop it!
He's no weirdo at all!
この人は怪しいとか そんなんじゃ
Huh?
What are you gettin' so serious for?
何ムキになってんだよ
Because we've been living together, and
I know what a good person he is!
一緒に暮らしていて
いい人だって分かってるんだから
いっ！ ぎ… 一緒に暮らしてるだあ？
Living together!?
Did you two already do it!?
もう やっちまったのか！
Don't be ridiculous!
変なこと
Even when you've already got me!?
俺という男がありながら！
Oh, is that how it is?
そうなのか
違います！ ただの幼馴染みです！
It's not like that!
He's only a childhood friend.
Only...
た ただ… ただの
Only? What do you mean only!?
ただのって何だあ！
And where the hell did this guy
pop out from anyway!?
大体 こいつは
いきなり出てきて何なんだあ！
He was injured, so I couldn't just
leave him where he was.
この人は怪我をしていて
放っておけないっていうか
That's why I...
それで その…
Ah, of course. Yeah, that's what I figured.
そうだよなあ　そうだと思ったぜ
I'm just sayin' I won't put up with anyone
coming between you and me.
俺とお前の間に水を差すような
奴がいて たまるかっての
So, have you finished your
business, dear Prince?
で 用事は済んだのか？
皇子様
What was that!?
This ain't got nothing to do with you!
んーだとぉ？ 関係ねえ奴ぁ
すっこんでろおー！
It has plenty to do with me.
関係は十分にある
This girl is the one who saved my life.
She is family to me.
その子は自分の恩人であり
家族だ
ぬう！
Eruruu...
エルルゥ
Yes?
はい
Have I said anything that offended you?
何か 君の機嫌を損ねるようなことを
言ってしまっただろうか
What?
You have been silent for some time now.
ずっと黙っているが
It's not that.
違うんです
その どちらかといえば
If anything, I'm happy right now.
嬉しくて
Happy?
嬉しい？
Haven't I been a burden on you?
迷惑じゃなかったか？
そんな！
Not at all!
今日は私の方が助けられちゃいました
Today, you were the one who rescued me.
Nuwangi wasn't always like that.
ヌワンギも 昔は
あんな風じゃなかったのに
I'm sure... No person is tainted with
greed right from the start.
最初から欲にまみれた人間などいないさ
Excuse me...
あの…
ああ　何を言ってるんだろうな 自分は
Listen to me, what am I talking about?
Damn!
クソー！
クソー クソ クソ クソ クソ クソッ！
Damn it, damn it, damn it,
damn it, damn it, damn it!
That frickin' wise ass!
舐めた口利きやがって
Damn, I hate that sonnuva bitch!
ムカつくぜ あの野郎！
うぐ！ うう
What the hell's with them,
scarin' me like that?
何だよ おどかしやがって
Hey! Whoa, stop!
-ああっ こら 待てえ！
-ガァウウウー！
りじりじぃーやああー！
ガァウウウー！
Then, like we thought, that voice...
じゃあ やっぱり この声は
Yes, it is Mutikapa-sama.
ムティカパ様じゃ
It would seem that someone has
desecrated the forest,
誰かがタムヤにでも
いたずらしたと見える
perhaps by smashing one of the small
shrines or some other mischief.
This is terrible!
何てことだ
Who could have done it?
いったい 誰が…
うっ　ふふぅ
He was with me the whole time!
この人は ずっと私といました！
Huh? Oh, right, I know.
ああ？ ああ 分かってる
No one's accusing the kid. Right?
誰も あんちゃんを疑っちゃいねえよ
なあ
Aruruu...
アルルゥ
You're being noisy...
うるさい
Because we're talking about
something important. Come on.
大事な話だから
ほら
Sorry about that.
悪かったなあ
Think nothing of it.
いえ 気にしないでください
It is understandable that I would be suspected.
疑われるのは仕方のないことですから
I'm tellin' ya not to talk like that!
そう言うなって
Look, these guys are just a
little worked up, that's all.
こいつらも ちょーっと
ビビっちまってるだけだからよお
あっはは…
Who is this Mutikapa?
その ムティカパというのは？
I'll tell you about Mutikapa-sama.
ムティカパ様はな
She is a servant of Yahnaun the
Divine and master of the forest.
ヤーナゥン・カミの使い
森のぬし様なんじゃ
She eternally protects the forest from the
devastation we might wreak upon it.
わしら人が森を荒らさんようにと
ずっと守っておるんじゃ
Then we need to do something to appease her.
何とか お怒りを鎮めてもらわないと
Yeah, or we won't be able to go
into the forest anymore.
ああ 森に入れなくなる
Then we might as well exterminate her.
だったら いっそ退治しちまえば
What are you talking about!?
なーに言ってるんだ
There's no way we'd be able to stand up
to the master of the forest!
森のぬし様にかなうわけあるめえ
Mutikapa-sama is strong, agile, and wise.
ムティカパ様は強く 素早く 賢い
And above all is that body of hers,
which neither arrow nor spear can pierce.
そして何より 矢も槍も
貫くことができない その体じゃ
If we do anything to agitate her,
it will only bring disaster upon us.
下手に刺激すれば
わしらが悲惨なことになるだけじゃよ
Chief!
村長
The shrine was smashed after all!
やっぱり タムヤが壊れちょった
Then we should fix it right away
and present an offering!
じゃあ すぐに直して そんでお供え物を
It's no use.
無理じゃよ
Plus, the rain keeps on picking up.
雨もますます つようなっちょるし
However...
しかし
A god should not be angered over
something like that.
そんなことで神は怒るはずがない
How do you know?
何で そんなことが分かるんだ？
いえ
Well, I just have the feeling...
ただ そんな気がして
とにかく
In any case, come nightfall let's try to
avoid going outside if at all possible.
夜になったら
できるだけ外に出ないように
We'll go and repair the shrine
as soon as the rain lets up.
タムヤは雨が上がり次第直しに行くよ
It looks like the bleeding has stopped.
もう出血は無いみたいですね
That is thanks to the care you have given me.
エルルゥの看病のおかげだよ
おばあちゃんの薬のおかげですよ
It's thanks to my grandma's medicine.
She's the world's best healer after all.
おばあちゃんは世界一の薬師なんです
Eruruu?
エルルゥ
はい
Yes?
自分はなぜ あんなことを
What made me say such a thing?
What do you mean?
あんなことって…
Something impels me...
何かが 自分を突き動かすんだ
What in the world am I doing?
自分は 何をいったい…
Relax...
落ち着いて
Please relax.
落ち着いてください
I am making everyone very uneasy.
自分は 皆を不安にさせてしまっている
Dwelling on things like that will take
its toll on you physically.
思い詰めると体に毒ですよ
今は元気になることだけを
考えてください
For now, think only of getting better.
You'll be all right.
大丈夫です
I'm sure your memories will come back
once you're well again.
元気になれば
きっと記憶も戻ってきますから
I can rest easy hearing that from you.
エルルゥにそう言われると 安心するよ
You will probably be a superb healer one day.
エルルゥは 素晴らしい
薬師になるだろうな
Thank you.
ありがとう
You're very welcome.
どういたしまして
グゥ グルルル…
ガァウウウー！
ガアアー！ グルルル…
ワァウウウー！
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
孤独の中求む
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
魂から結びつき 私を恋い温めて
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼 祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼 弱きいのちが消えても
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
くりかえす 輪廻の流れ辿り
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
くりかえし 詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
Ruler of the Wild Forest